Don, congratulations.
What kind of led you to re-up here and
how fast did it come together?
Um
I'd say just like being in the same
system for more than 1 year.
And you know, I was I was really
comfortable and um
meshed well with our defensive
coordinator and D-line coach.
And um
I couldn't
>> [clears throat]
>> take that for granted, so I resigned
with the Saints cuz I wanted to run it
back.
What was it about those last few games
getting in at the end of the year that
you think uh you showed and did you
notice uh
any like improvement in your game, too?
Do you think that led to them re-signing
you?
I mean, yeah. I mean, if you look
at like the stats, I don't think we went
over 100 rushing yards like against us.
And we played like really good running
backs like Tony Pollard from Tennessee
Um you know,
uh
dude from Atlanta.
>> [clears throat]
>> And our defense didn't skip a beat. I
mean,
I know Bryan came when I was late in the
season and Nathan Shepherd. And you
know, those are two guys that played I
think like 60% of our defensive snaps
the whole year. So, those were like two
main key roles and
>> [snorts]
>> you know, when they plugged me and
Christian Barmore in, it was almost like
our defense didn't skip a beat on first
and second down stopping the run. So, it
was nice.
And I think that was like one of the
main things that kind of like resonated
with me and the coaching staff is I'm
not just like
a backup
or like a guy you can plug in when
someone needs a break. Like I can be in
a game and take it over as well.
Don, you lifted some guys who are sort
of like uh
D-ends in a 3-4 and nose tackles in a
3-4. I mean, is that is that the
versatility you feel comfortable at both
spots?
Well, I mean, Bryan really isn't a
D-end. He's more of a 3-tech. Same as
Shepherd, but
um
I mean, I can play that in a two and a
nose, for sure.
And what do you like so much about uh
Staley's system and how you fit in it?
Um I think it's designed for bigger-body
guys instead of like you get some of
those D-tackles that are more 6-2
sawed-off, you know, twitchy fast.
And I think Staley's defense
for stopping the run
is designed for bigger bodies to get in
there and plug up gaps and, you know,
cut the ball off. And I feel like that's
perfect for, you know, my style of play.
What what have you learned about
yourself as a player since joining the
Saints organization?
You know, since coming over from from
Washington.
Um
I feel like mostly just belief, like
you know, I'm not just
um
you know, just a 20-snap a game guy.
Like I can be in there, you know, three
or four quarters and rotate in with
some dogs and, you know,
be a part of a good defense. I mean, I
was playing under Jonathan Allen and
Daron Payne in Washington and
you know, I played good ball, but it's
kind of hard when you have, you know,
two first-rounders and guys who'll go
down in their Washington Hall of Fame
for like
um TFLs, so
you know, coming here and taking that
same grit I learned from them and um
trying to plug and play with the Saints,
so I feel like that definitely helped me
out a lot just by realizing like how
good I really am
versus just being like a second-string
guy there.
Do you feel like you were able to
improve kind of behind the scenes um
you know, before you got in there at the
end of the year and then you were hurt a
little bit, but just that time between
being healthy and before getting your
opportunity near the end of the year?
I mean, yeah. I was pretty banged up in
the start of the year.
Um
Like my [clears throat] back was having
spasms and
I think right before we left for LA, I
was finally starting to feel better and
then
we came back from LA and I tore my pec a
week later, so it was definitely a rough
start of the season, but I feel like
once um
>> [clears throat]
>> I healed up and I showed them I was
ready and they were able to put me in,
I feel like I made my reps count.
And you know, with Demario gone, Cam
still unsigned, Taysom's up in the air,
Alvin, you know, who knows. How
different do you think this locker room
would be if none of them come back next
year and um what would you guys have to
do kind of collectively as a group if
they're they're not back?
Um I think definitely be like
um
like
I feel like a lot of the younger guys
will have to step up
for leadership roles that it comes to
the team cuz, you know, that we'd be
losing
we are losing a lot of good leaders on
offense and defense, whether they retire
or not or you know, but I feel like it
definitely
it'll definitely have to be the younger
guys that are on year four or five that
start taking over that leadership role
on the team.
But it'll definitely it'll definitely be
a learning curve because
you know, those guys know so much
football over their years they've
played, so they understand, you know,
what people are going through or like
week 13
how everybody is uh banged up or waiting
for a bye week. You know, having
Double-D
standing up in front of the defense and
reminding people what we're working for,
you know, that was nice and I think that
will be missed and that will be
definitely something that like we'll
have to implement as a
team players
to get everybody on the same page.
Sticking with the locker room, um
you know, you spoke to some of the
leadership that's exiting the building.
Just what kind of, you know, vibe do you
try to bring to the locker room? I know
you got the boom box in there. Like
what's maybe a couple go-tos when you're
when you are playing the music and it's
just a like what kind of energy do you
like to bring?
I always try to challenge like Godchaux
to smile
or just mess with him. I always mess
with Bryan.
I always try to keep like some good
tunes on, like some old-school stuff
that like maybe Cam or Double-D or
somebody's listened to back in the day
and like
I don't know. I just try to like bring
like a
a good attitude every day cuz, you know,
some people
you know, they play like 50 snaps in
that game, they're beat up. The last
thing I want to do is strap up their
cleats again, but you know, like
bringing that like fun attitude to
practice or to like meetings every day
is good.
And uh
just uh is the robe new? Uh
Is that a
Uh I know, dude. It's You All right,
it's like 30
I'd say it's like 20° outside
here in Illinois, like
like I got snow.
Oh, wow. So, it's like this robe is
keeping the big boy warm.
>> [laughter]
>> I got to get down in New Orleans and get
my blood thin again.
Mhm. Up here, it's it's too cold, dude.
Like I got pipes that's froze over the
last couple days. I had to like chip out
drywall to
re-solder pipes. Like I'm out here. I
need to get back to football. I'm out
here working like a blue-collar dude
right now.
Mhm.
Well, hey, congrats again. You know,
you'll be there soon.